<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Works on Filip Dobrocky</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/works/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Works on Filip Dobrocky</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Filip Dobrocky</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:26:52 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/works/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Geof칩nie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/works/geofonie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:26:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/works/geofonie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Geof칩nie is the result of the Trycht칳콏 2024 open call, the goal of which was to create a site-specific collective sound installation for Brno&amp;rsquo;s former limestone quarry H치dy, now a nature reserve and a popular recreation area on the city.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arty캜ok TV&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://artycok.tv/cs/post/sonda-festival-lom-hady&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position:relative;padding-top:66%;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe style=&#34;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;&#34; src=&#34;https://artycok.tv/cs/embed/03dd85be-ed5b-421d-90d3-89ef4f5b2cb5&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The open call brought together artists of diverse backgrounds and resulted in a multi-layered spatial sound installation exploring the location&amp;rsquo;s geology. The constellation of objects, forming an IoT network, generates a varying soundscape by the means of sonification (scanning the surface of various limestones), or live processing the sound of limestones dissolving in acid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/works/structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 13:29:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/works/structure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Structure is concieved as an audiovisual performance using generative 3D graphics and spatial sound. Synesthetic audiovisual gestalts are formed by means of micro-relationships of image and sound.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;      &lt;div&#xA;          style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;iframe&#xA;          src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/995408390?dnt=0&#34;&#xA;            style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allow=&#34;fullscreen&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The resulting shapes of image and sound are instatiations of an abstract algotithmic structure working in virtual 3D domain - a strictly defined structure creating structures that are seemingly unpredictable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lithic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/works/lithic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 14:29:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/works/lithic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first multimedia project at Janacek Academy of Performing Arts and my first try at an installation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The subject of the piece are stones, all collected at local former quarry H치dy. I focused on the sonic and haptic qualities of stones, with a motivation grounded in phenomenology rather than geology. The stones attracted me with their visual purity and universality in meaning. A stone is usually associated with something rigid and stable - I question that with electro-mechanical excitation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cycle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/works/cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 14:43:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/works/cycle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Originaly an electroacoustic composition, later video and live performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main object of interest is the 洧눆洧눍洧눇洧눜洧눇洧눐洧눉 - a mode of transport, a lifestyle or a target of a culture war. In the hegemony of automobilism, this simple and efficient way of getting through the city is often considered &amp;ldquo;extreme&amp;rdquo;. The aim of this recording is emancipation of the bicycle. Field recordings made during city commutes, the noise of cars, sounds of bicycles, bicycle played as a musical instrument. Cycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phone Orchestra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/works/phone-orchestra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 14:46:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/works/phone-orchestra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interactive performance where the specators become performers, interpreting a visual score using the flashlights on their phones.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The piece is one of the results of the first iteration of collaborative project Trycht칳콏 by &lt;a href=&#34;https://svitava.org/&#34;&gt;SVITAVA transmedia art lab&lt;/a&gt;. The idea came collectively, the interactive visuals were created by Mat칰코 Stenko and I took care of the programming, computer vision and sound design.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;      &lt;div&#xA;          style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;iframe&#xA;          src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/999268353?dnt=0&#34;&#xA;            style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allow=&#34;fullscreen&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was built using OpenCV in Python feeding data to Max via OSC, which in turn fed video data to Resolume Arena using NDI through Wi-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
